（狗吠叫）
弗朗西:漫長的一天。
（吠叫繼續
在遠處）
（模糊的喋喋不休）
愛琳？
謝謝,愛。
莎拉:更像
驢子闖進來了,瑪麗。
他媽的,喜歡,
我們本來可以是任何東西。
教師,護士,理髮師。
（笑）理髮師？
不要那麼雄心勃勃,莎拉。
你不只是聽到她的聲音嗎？
叫我們驢子？
實際的屁股,喜歡。
-但是真是個屁,希拉,女孩。
-（笑聲）
（警笛哀嚎）
（模糊的喊叫）
瑪麗: 我的兒子！（抽泣）
不！
馬克！（歇斯底裡地哭泣）
（瑪麗輕輕地哭泣）
（莎拉用蓋爾語唱歌）
如果我什麼都不做,
我正在教這個小屁孩
如何游泳。
莎拉:愛琳。
耶穌基督,姑娘。
耶拉...
為了他媽的緣故。
他們真的生活在水面上
他們都沒有學會如何做。
你知道的
這是傳統,愛琳。
什麼,知道是運氣不好？
如果他們不會游泳,
他們不會跳進去
並説明其他人。
一群自私的流氓,
太擔心了
關於他們自己的皮膚。
-（奧斯卡咕咕）
-怎麼了,奧斯卡,愛情？
醒來哭泣三,
每晚四次。
-災難,就像。
-耶穌基督,
我記得和你在一起的夜晚。
永遠睡不著。
騙子告訴我
我只能讓你哭。
我該怎麼做？
- 聽到每一個噪音。
-（咕咕）
你是更容易的孩子,
公平地說。
（咕咕）
（用蓋爾語演唱）
（模糊的喋喋不休）
布萊恩:進展如何？
我有一段時間沒見你了。
事情怎麼樣？
很高興見到你。（笑）
（笑聲）
嗨,丹。
布萊恩·奧哈拉？管他呢
你在這裡嗎？
耶穌基督,你的大小。
你越強壯...
過來這裡。
布萊恩:我們都更廣泛了
更聰明的是丹男孩的樣子。
-過了一會兒。
-好傢伙,事情怎麼樣？
布萊恩。
-基督,布萊恩
-（笑）
媽媽,看看你,呵呵。
-你的頭髮。
你一點也沒變。
-（哭泣）
（奧斯卡哭泣）
布萊恩:這是誰,對吧？
這是我的寶貝弟弟,是嗎？
什麼！不不不。
上帝啊。（笑）
哦,來找我。
哦。（氣喘吁吁）
嗯,帕迪,事情怎麼樣？
愛琳:你是個婊子養的兒子。
-布萊恩！
-布萊恩:愛琳！
搞什麼！
你在這裡幹什麼？
現在是「回合時間」
我回來了,不是嗎？
（歎息）
- 布萊恩:莎拉。
-布萊恩。
愛琳:馬克·菲茨需要死
等你回來
對我們來說,是嗎？
什麼？
這就是為誰準備的？
啊,他媽的我,是的。
我很抱歉。
只要給我一秒鐘。
瑪麗,嗯...
我很抱歉,瑪麗。
-我很抱歉。
-瑪麗:謝謝。
帕迪多久了
一直都是這樣的？
好幾年了
在此階段。
-回來一定很奇怪。
-嗯。
可能一模一樣,
但是,是嗎？
（布萊恩和愛琳笑）
布萊恩:她會停止去嗎？
愛琳:哦,不是一秒鐘
你一直都在走。
（奧斯卡哭泣）
愛琳:一分鐘,愛。
（車輛接近）
布萊恩:那個爸爸,是嗎？
你應該出去見見他。
他喜歡這樣。
繼續。
-你好嗎？
-哦,是的,是的。
（模糊的喋喋不休）
愛琳:看到他們很奇怪
握手。
（愛琳歎息）他是不同的,
不是嗎？成長為自己。
你估計嗎？
愛琳:一位母親知道。
（腳步聲接近）
你臉上的表情。
-別那麼震驚,夥計。
-什麼？
-缺點:她喂過你嗎？
- 布萊恩:呃,不。還沒有。
缺點:難以置信
他回家了,對吧？
很高興現在回家,好吧。
所以,你在澳大利亞。
未取得聯繫
和我們在一起多久？
你會得到一個概念,
突然間,回家了。
狗屎天氣,他媽的所有工作,
而不告訴任何人？
是的。那是關於
它的大小,是的。
來吧,你為什麼回來了,喜歡？
呃。。。
稻田的牡蠣。
基督。哦,你開始了
從無到有。
你省錢了嗎？
牡蠣需要工作。
它們並不便宜。
但我們仍然有
它的許可證。
我保留了付款。
每年
因為Con放棄了它。
以防萬一。
（嗡嗡聲）
（伴有咕嚕聲）
-向前傾斜。
-好的。
-布萊恩:是這樣嗎？
-是的。
-布萊恩:那好嗎？
布萊恩: 我明白了
你照顧它。
缺點:我的父親
再也無法忍受了,
你走了
並一直不復存在。
就是這樣。沒有其他選擇。
不想工作它
與其他人一起。
耶穌基督,這是不真實的。
缺點:地面的
部分有點軟。
您必須更換
你的一些棧橋。
查找供應商
為您的牡蠣和袋子。
從種子開始
或者半個成年人,然後。
至少一年
在它們成熟之前,轉為利潤。
你必須找到
另一筆收入。
但你自己也知道這一點。
那不算什麼
你無法管理,
不過,布萊恩。是嗎？
不麻煩。
為了他媽的緣故。（笑）
（叮叮噹噹）
哦,對不起,愛琳。
忘了打卡了。
-給我一分鐘時間。
-不著急,愛。
布萊恩:好看的牡蠣。
謝謝弗朗西
如果他們抓住了我們,那就有點瘋狂了。
-愛琳:哦,
不要對我說。
-（笑）
快點吧,你會的。加油。
我在等媽。
（咕嚕咕嚕）
-晚餐見,是嗎？
-去吧,是的,走開。
注意安全。
-布萊恩:啪！
-（熱鬧的愛爾蘭音樂播放）
（愛琳·百靈）
（歡呼）
布萊恩:謝謝你們,夥計們。
嗨,小夥子,事情怎麼樣？
丹:你來了。
在這裡,採取一些這樣的措施。繼續。
弗朗西:週刊。給我們一首歌。
-走吧。
-謝謝,媽媽。
-你去吧,丹。
-莎拉:好的,好的。
我會為你做一個。
♪ 我們在黑暗中行走
♪ 我們晚上出去走<>
（女人舒什）
♪ 而且不是像戀人那樣
♪ 二乘二,來回,
♪ 但它是一個接一個
♪ 在黑暗中一個接一個
♪ 我們晚上出去走<>
澳大利亞呢？
♪ 當我們徘徊時
<>穿過草地
-你的是什麼
那裡最喜歡的地方？
-嗯。
♪ 我們可以聽到對方通過
你會感到驚訝的
我看得多麼少,愛琳。
如果我知道你在哪裡,
我會去拜訪你。
♪ 我們晚上出去走<>
那將有
一切都很好,但是...
你沒有錯過太多。
♪ 草如此又黑又高
（笑）
此外,它是
世界上最好的東西
回到這裡...
和你在一起。
♪ 月亮倒下了
♪ 我們晚上出去走<>
♪ 如果我把你的手握在我的手裡
♪ 我可以發光,我可以發光
♪ 就像清晨的陽光
♪ 就像太陽 ♪
（全程鼓掌）
-你去哪裡？
-瑪麗:我能再買一個嗎,丹？
-我要去抽煙。
- 不,不,不
你不會去任何地方。
-我們得回家了。
-不,我不想回家。
-我不在乎。
-我還不想回家。
（喃喃自語）
瑪麗,對吧？
-瑪麗:沒有。
-來吧。
弗朗西:我告訴你
計數低。
希拉:再數一遍。
弗朗西:我數了兩遍。
沒有足夠的袋子。
希拉:你告訴我
如何做我的工作,法蘭西？
弗朗西:某人的
試圖欺騙我。
它會出來嗎
你他媽的工資？
希拉:聽著,我只是
給你你所要求的。
弗朗西:哦,等一下。
你是說
它和我有關！
-現在是我的錯,是嗎？
-嘿,嘿,什麼
這裡的故事,小夥子們？
這個小婊子
試圖欺騙我。
他媽的,法蘭西。
沒有
附近有足夠多的袋子。
其餘的在哪裡
我他媽的半個成年人？
我相信他們都在那裡。
你把它們填好了,
不是嗎？
無法想像
我怎麼可能沒有。
我以完全相同的方式拆分它們
就像我上次做的那樣,喜歡。
因為你是個白癡,
這就是原因。鄧尼斯在這裡嗎？
愛琳:我沒有
看到他了嗎,沒有。
這是一個容易犯的錯誤,
女孩。快點走吧。
（海鷗吱）
裡面很瘋狂,
不是嗎？
羞辱你和法蘭西
我們不得不早點回家
那天晚上。
我一直在佔用空間,
他不開心
關於它。
擦了擦他的手
在最後一晚之後。
但在這裡,我哭出了我的眼睛
就好像他就是那個人一樣
誰傷了我的心。
不過,忍不住。
慢慢來。
我回來了
在我父母的房子里
住了幾個晚上。
時間不言而喻
很快進入透視。
他的話很殘酷。
不過,他只是
像其他人一樣。
我們都是上帝的受造物
不知情。
（愛琳歎息）
（愛琳會說蓋爾語）
（喘息）
布萊恩:那是四條鮭魚。
兩百給你。
司機:好人。
-布萊恩:謝謝。
-乾杯。
布萊恩:工作進展如何,康？
啊,我想是創造出來的。
這是從哪裡來的？
你認為你是
一個硬漢,是嗎？
與系統作鬥爭。
偷獵,
好像你不知道更好。
這不是你沒有做的事
回到過去,騙子。
我從來沒有出去過
在春潮時。
馬可肯定死了
做同樣的事情。
那就是
你會發生什麼
最終,否則你會被抓住。
所有指向同一目的,
喜歡。愚蠢。
耶穌基督,輕裝上陣,夥計。
她為你偷的包
還不夠,不是嗎？
你持續了多長時間
誠實行事
牡蠣？
反正比我想像的要長。
公平競爭。
你一直告訴我
我能做什麼,不能做什麼,
但我保持
帕迪的農場正在走。
你父親只想說
你不必採取
這樣的風險。
謝謝媽。
（水湧出）
（海鷗吱
在遠處）
這是怎麼回事,小夥子？
檢查是否沒有任何內容
我可以利用。
基督,事情是
那可是壞事吧？
你就像一隻老鼠。
其中大部分是我的舊狗屎。
它早已成為任何用途。
投資一些新事物
為了你自己。
給自己
反正有機會,小夥子。
告訴我們,什麼...
你明天要做什麼？
（點擊舌頭）呃。。。
晚上出門
潮汐過後,我會說。
所以,你是自由的
早上,我服用嗎？
可以有一份工作給你。
我的意思是,使用這些肯定
我可以付錢給你
上面有點額外。
這很艱難,不是嗎...
自己動手嗎？
實在是太過分了,
一個人。
這是教訓
你父親學會了。
這些將適合布萊恩,
他們會嗎？
你沒事吧,瑪麗？
我一直以為我聽到了馬克
當我獨自一人在這裡時。
晚上有聲音...
可能是他
在這個地方移動。
奇怪的舒適。
（歎息）
謝謝,愛。
（氣喘吁吁）
弗朗西:布萊恩,
出來他媽的。
你能快點嗎？
（咕嚕咕嚕）
哦。
-哦。
-（笑）
必須保持警惕
在潮汐上,夥計。
（呻吟）
布萊恩:某個早晨,
稻田男孩。
一切都在改變,
但。。。
一模一樣
當你,我,
和騙子在工作。
喝冷茶
從7UP瓶中取出
在晴朗的日子里,
沒有比這更好的了。
你在那裡嗎？
（輕輕地咕嚕咕嚕）
狗屎...
他媽的。。。
迪克,波洛克斯,屁股。
（輕輕咕咕）
你什麼都沒說？
愛琳:
我沒有告訴他任何事情,沒有。
九個月後,這個傢伙。
他是一個需要説明的小傢伙。
通常的家庭特徵。
男孩就是男孩。
粘在他們母親的奶頭上。
看起來很聰明。
你想要嗎
和我們一起下來？
愛琳:我應該回家了。
我們有一個早期的
在上午。
引領全國
幾天。
顯示小個子
世界還有更多。
布萊恩:來吧。
讓我們來展示一下。
哦。
（咯咯笑）
（門打開）
（門關閉）
（笑）
我。。。我不知道。
-聖誕毛衣。
-聖誕毛衣,
就是這個。
好吧,到...
你可以去
在世界任何地方。
無條件。
你會去哪裡？
你知道嗎...
我寧願只是...（歎息）
把歲月捲回來...
然後坐你
和你父親下來
使你們表現得像成年人一樣。
這很好
想像你相處融洽,
住在一個屋簷下。
但我為此感到自豪
不過,你現在是。
就好像作品本身
是開始
和它的結束。
莎拉:嘿,丹。
- 丹:嘿,莎拉。
-我能買一杯威士忌嗎？
當然可以。是的。
你想再喝一杯嗎？
不。不,留在那裡。
我會得到的,好吧。
讓我來告訴你這個。
哦,你很偉大。
不過,謝謝。
你出去過夜？
我們將在這之後看到現在。
嗯嗯。
我簡直不敢相信
老實說,你還在這裡。
我以為你會有
早就拋棄了這個地方。
我不知道
你為什麼會這麼想。
我需要的一切
在這裡。
不用去
尋找它。
嗯。
比如？
不。我們曾經有過
一起好瘋狂
當我們年輕的時候,不是嗎？
-我們？
-嗯嗯嗯。
那是很久以前的事了。
我不會掛在上面
如果我是你。
你在喝什麼？
當然,去吧,給我一個驚喜。
我,嗯...兩個又一樣。
-呃,她有
威士卡,是她嗎？
- 和:嗯嗯嗯。
-（叮叮噹噹）
-（模糊的喋喋不休）
布萊恩:你去吧。
有...
退潮時間是什麼時候？
繼續吧,你會嗎？
好吧。晚上,寵物。
晚安。
莎拉:我可能會借用
那讓你的頂端
其中一個晚上,愛琳。
愛琳: 我來見你
明天,姑娘。
（烏鴉吱吱叫）
愛琳:對不起,小夥子們。
（模糊的喋喋不休）
-早上好。
- 所有:早上好。
女人1:
你昨晚出去了嗎？
女人2:不,不。
我不是。你出去了嗎？
（模糊的喋喋不休）
晚安,是嗎？
女人:瑪麗,看。
-看看那個。
-停止皮帶。愛琳。
-真菌。
-狗屎。
女人:我們也有真菌。
鄧尼斯:讓我看看！
-檢查股票的其餘部分。
-（呼吸沉重）
鄧尼斯:把這些扔掉。
他媽的緣故！
真是一場災難。
（繼續呼吸沉重）
女人: 耶穌！
-莎拉？
-不要碰我。
巡警西部:
特此警告您
停止種植
所有牡蠣持有量
直至另行通知,
可處以失去許可證
如果被發現違規
暫停。
您今天收穫的任何牡蠣
必須銷毀。
（模糊的喋喋不休）
布萊恩: 你有嗎
對我有什麼工作嗎？
弗朗西:不,我不會
再次需要你
有一段時間,沒有。
保持低頭
像他們的其餘部分一樣,
你會很宏偉。
我會拿走你欠我的,所以。
（法蘭西笑）
弗朗西:好的,小夥子們,
讓我們把它們都扔掉。是的。
（門關閉）
（淋浴運行）
-女人1:我們是什麼
現在應該做,喜歡嗎？
-女人2:哦。
女人3:同樣的事情發生了,
大約七八年前,
不是嗎？
幾乎被摧毀
牡蠣養殖者。
女人2:他們的想法
在家裡無所事事。
對任何人都沒有好處。
瑪麗:似乎得到了
對她來說越來越糟,
不是嗎？
可憐的克拉圖。
她不是故意要咬你。
如果法蘭西做了什麼,
她需要大聲說出來。
（模糊的喋喋不休）
-愛琳:嘿,愛。
-希亞。
你忙嗎？
不是很好的時間,沒有。
我只是在做
房子里有幾份工作。
媽媽說他們沒見過你
在工廠幾天內。
氣味終於來了
找到你,是嗎？
不。
發生了什麼事,姑娘？
我在這裡,你知道的。
如果你需要任何東西。是的？
是的。
我會讓你回到它。
謝謝。
（車門打開、關閉）
（發動機起動,轉速）
（歎息）
（布萊恩·葛籣茨）
（電話鈴聲）
缺點:你好？
愛琳。
愛琳。事情如何？
嘿,你可能會跟著我
通過這裏現在。
我們現在就在這裡,看。
騙子怎麼了？
布萊恩在哪裡,邁克？
很抱歉拖拽您
一路進城。
你一定很高興
有布萊恩
和你一起回到房子里。
當然,你瞭解你自己。
你估計嗎？
上帝知道我的女兒
搬回了房子里,
我們會撕扯條
彼此關閉。
他是澳大利亞,是嗎？
澳大利亞,是的。
這不總是這樣嗎？
傷透了母親的心。
完全。
看,有人提出過索賠
關於村裡的一次襲擊
幾周前
由一位年輕女子創作
誰在丹·內爾的酒吧
當晚
4月18日。
布萊恩說他在家
那天晚上和你在一起。
是嗎？
是的,他是。
-他沒有出去
或任何階段的任何東西...
- 沒有。不。
你會再說一遍
在法庭上？
我會。是的。
好吧。看,我知道,
嗯,布萊恩的
一個努力工作的人。
是這樣嗎？
我會給他一個喊叫
現在在那裡為你。就一分鐘。
這有點多,邁克,不是嗎,
把我拖出來
半夜
只是問一個簡單的問題？
我們必須被看作是
做我們的工作,愛琳。
（門打開）
（車門關閉）
（深深地歎息）
你沒事吧？
哼。需要喝幾品脫。
我的麵包車正在回去的路上。
我們可能會把它撿起來。
還有其他人出來嗎,
你還記得嗎？
我不能告訴你。
我離開你之後發生了什麼？
我們喝了幾杯。
我們沒有做的任何事情
想當年。
那是什麼意思？
上帝啊。。。
我最好回去嗎
去他媽的澳大利亞？
是這樣嗎？被拖拽
變成這個狗屎。
你不會去
任何地方,好嗎？
你聽到我說話了嗎？
（水流）
（烏鴉嗤之）
謝謝,媽媽。
瑪麗:暫停
不會持久,是重點。
幾周後,
水會冷卻,
所有這些都會神奇地重置。
牡蠣養殖者再次創造它,
就像什麼都沒發生過一樣。
這就是時間的作用。
教訓浪費在年輕人身上。
女人:愛琳？愛琳。
是否有任何額外的時間
我可以在下周接機嗎？
你可能會報導莎拉的轉變。
你沒收到她的消息嗎？
我有。是的。
我們有衛兵進入我們。
耶拉,不...
他們只是在看
與客戶交談
幾周後。
這是一個安靜的夜晚...
這就是我告訴他們的。
現在會更在他們的隊伍中
要研究
外國拖網漁船強姦
我們的海洋,對吧？
他們的雙手被綁住,
那是什麼
無論如何,他們都會告訴你。
為什麼耶穌不是
出生在澳大利亞？
嘿。
-啊,因為他是...
-（模糊的喋喋不休）
艾瑪:晚上,小夥子們。
-丹:好的。
-是的。
你和我們在一起嗎？
明天又來了,姑娘？
我是,是的。謝謝。
-夜給你。
-丹:夜。
布萊恩:晚上。
因為沒有智者...
也沒有處女。
（布萊恩笑）
-好吧。
-嗯。
丹:好人。
-來吧...
-（模糊的喋喋不休）
-丹:夜。
-老人:夜之歸你。晚上。
（敲門）
布萊恩在嗎？
（奧斯卡咕咕）
費用將是
對他不利。
他需要展示自己
在地區法院前
今天週,
和初步還押候審
將製作
在法官面前。
為了他媽的緣故,邁克。
看,只要確保
他在那裡,你會嗎？
愛琳:你告訴他們的
那天晚上你沒有出去。
但我們都知道
不過,這是一個謊言。
愛琳,你對此瞭解多少？
弗朗西虐待她
多少年,
沒有人
想什麼都想。
突然間,每個人都認為
布萊恩是問題所在。
誰從不伸出援手
在他生命中的一個女人身上。
你自己說了些什麼
是在發生在莎拉身上之後。
也許是法蘭西,是的。
但你不想要
聽聽她的聲音？
你沒事吧？
鄧尼斯:莎拉的
今天不會再來了嗎？
（模糊的喋喋不休）
你什麼時候回來？
我不知道。
會發生什麼
如果他回來受審？
水稻:
♪ 在清醒和睡覺時
♪ 我渴望在那裡
♪ 再次行走
♪ 那些善良的街道
♪ 我出生的地方
加油。
它是如何完成的？
嗯？
♪ 和男孩們
來自巴爾納·斯萊德
♪ 誰打獵
布萊恩和帕迪:
♪ 對於鹪鹩... ♪
（笑）
什麼都沒有
你錯了,帕迪,夥計。
嗯。
你只是在玩一把戲
在我們其他人身上。
你還有哪些其他歌曲？
<>·麥嗯？
也許是野生漫遊者？
好人。
嗯。
邁克:申訴人
等了一個星期
在向她報告之前
並聲稱她是
跟著到當地的碼頭
在襲擊當晚
並且被告
隨後強姦了她
在那兒。
被告的母親
已經提供了他
有不在場證明,法官。
她重申了這一說法。
她和被告
在房子里
在工作時間
當晚,
被告人仍保留
和她在一起的房子里
在工作時間
聲稱的攻擊？
我願意,閣下。是的。
法官:嗯。
這是一個嚴重的指控。
這也是第一次
被告
一直在法庭上。
現在我的意見
還不夠...
在證據書中
供國家起訴。
費用將被發回重審
回到民進黨
以獲取進一步說明。
我也相信這個收費
本來不應該是
被帶到法庭上。
呃,被告
可以自由離開。
下一步是什麼？
邁克:第15號檔,法官。
醉酒和無序。
（歎息）
（水湧出）
（呼氣）
（模糊的喋喋不休）
鄧尼斯:艾琳。
來這裡一分鐘,好嗎？
她最近出席的情況如何？
16個班次中有14個班次被遺漏。
莎拉:我可以做
日子一天過去了。請。
鄧尼斯:還有其他人嗎？
同時錯過了一個班次？
您可以讓我們知道
至少,你知道,
被叫來生病了。
但是我必須讓你走,姑娘。
你是對的,鄧尼斯。
我應該讓你知道
我發生了什麼事。
這是錯誤,是嗎？
一切都非常方便
但是,對你來說,不是嗎？
在法蘭西的牡蠣袋之間
和其他一切,
每個人都有他們的
他媽的閉上眼睛。
鄧尼斯:等等,等一下。
莎拉？
怎麼樣
牡蠣袋,莎拉？
來吧,小夥子們,專注,
回到工作上。
她是什麼意思
關於法蘭西的牡蠣,愛琳？
回家。
-什麼？
-回家一天。
（愛琳咯咯笑）
（咕咕）
奧斯卡,愛。
你不能只是帶走他
出入日托
沒有告訴我。
他不是你的兒子。
我不想要你
再照顧他了。
他媽的,愛琳。
她仍然是他的祖母。
如果你真的和她坐在一起,
你無法否認
發生了什麼事,愛琳。
-缺點:對她放輕鬆。
-愛琳:沒有。
為了他媽的緣故,
她需要聽到它。
（腳步聲後退）
缺點:我會和她談談。
你必須小心他。
無時無刻不在
莎拉在這裡,
當它是愛琳的房間。
我曾經和她媽媽開玩笑
關於你們倆,
我們會成為岳父母。
鄧尼斯:她在撒謊嗎
關於牡蠣袋,愛琳？
我得把你
直到我弄清楚
故事是什麼。
暫停令已經解除。
瘋狂幾個星期。
可能必須僱用
多了幾隻手。
（繼續模糊地談論）
丹:所以故事就這樣流傳開來,
幾個月來,
人們認為妻子死了
因為她摔倒了
井試圖拯救
火雞。
這是一些聰明的刺,
警衛。
女人1:那就太好了
讓你都過來
下個星期天彌撒后。
女人2:
給你休息一次。
（模糊的喋喋不休）
為你休息一下。
丹:好像他曾經是
等待這個問題
整個時間。
-（笑聲）
-女人1:我會做的
我的蘋果碎了。
“因為她是
一個討厭的婊子,這就是為什麼。
（笑聲）
希拉:兩個杜松子酒
和補品,請？
丹:今晚不行,不行。
希拉:什麼？
丹:我們保留權利
拒絕在這裡服務,愛。
幫自己一個忙
然後悄悄地走。
嗯？
你們都可以去他媽的地獄。
（笑聲）
丹:你留下來
你現在在哪裡,小夥子。
-抓住他,男孩們。
-（大聲笑）
你不去嗎
現在跟著她,嗯？
（大聲笑）
（咕嚕咕嚕）
布萊恩:我討厭
這些傳統的東西。
顯示面孔
只是為了它。
我可能懶得去。
做你想做的事。
（海鷗吱）
♪ 創造了夜晚的星星
♪ 我會做的
<>黑暗明亮
♪ 誰將承受
光給他們
♪ 我應該派誰來<>
♪ <>  主啊
♪ 主啊,是我
♪
♪ 你在夜裡打電話
♪ 主啊
♪ 如果你領導我
♪ 我將持有
♪ 我心中的子民
♪ <>  主啊
♪ 主啊,是我
♪
（雨拍）
♪ 你在夜裡打電話
♪ 主啊
♪ 如果你領導我
♪我會持有... ♪
（呼氣）
（呼吸沉重）
（歎息）
（叮叮噹噹）
今天是晚潮。
缺點:愛琳。
愛琳,你會進來嗎？
我會的,呃...
瑪麗:<>...主與你同在
婦女在婦女中祝福你,
果子是有福的
<>你的子宮耶穌
所有:聖母瑪利亞,天主之母,
現在就為我們罪人禱告
和在整點
我們的死亡。阿門。
瑪利亞:歡呼瑪利亞,充滿恩典,
耶和華與你同在。
你在婦女中間有福的藝術,
果實是有福的
你的子宮耶穌。
所有:聖母瑪利亞,天主之母,
現在就為我們罪人禱告
和在整點
我們的死亡。阿門。
瑪利亞:歡呼瑪利亞,充滿恩典,
耶和華與你同在。
你在婦女中間有福的藝術,
果實是有福的
你的子宮耶穌。
所有:聖母瑪利亞,天主之母,
現在就為我們罪人禱告
和在整點
我們的死亡。阿門。
瑪利亞:歡呼瑪利亞,充滿恩典,
耶和華與你同在。
你在婦女中間有福的藝術,
果實是有福的
你的子宮耶穌。
所有:聖母瑪利亞,天主之母,
現在就為我們罪人禱告
和在整點
我們的死亡。阿門。
瑪利亞:歡呼瑪利亞,充滿恩典,
耶和華與你同在。
你在婦女中間有福的藝術,
果實是有福的
你的子宮耶穌。
所有:聖母瑪利亞,天主之母,
現在就為我們罪人禱告
和在整點
我們的死亡。阿門。
瑪利亞:歡呼瑪利亞,充滿恩典,
耶和華與你同在...
（繼續模糊不清）
-男人:很抱歉你的損失。
-謝謝。
-女人:很抱歉你的損失。
-愛琳:謝謝。
謝謝。
女人1:我很抱歉
為了您的損失。
謝謝。
女人2:我很抱歉
為了您的損失。
（愛琳呼吸沉重）
-男人:我很抱歉你的損失。
-謝謝。
-男人:很抱歉你的損失。
我很抱歉你的損失,騙子。
缺點:謝謝,莎拉。
奈傑爾:莎拉！
-別他媽的碰她。
-奈傑爾:哀悼
為了你的損失,布萊恩。
-謝謝。
仿佛整個世界
顛倒了。
這他媽的一樣
一如既往,媽媽。
它可能看起來不同
如果你是那個轉彎的人。
但。。。
什麼都沒有改變。
相信我。
你是對的,踏入
不過,就像這樣。
我們要回家了。
休息一下。
你也應該這樣做。
（越野車車輪滾動）
（模糊的喋喋不休）
哼？
布萊恩:你想要什麼？
嗯,威士忌,我猜。
-你想要威士忌嗎？
-是的。
布萊恩: 在這裡,
請喝兩杯威士卡。
丹:兩杯威士卡,對吧？
艾瑪:是的。
布萊恩:你看起來很棒。
-艾瑪:謝謝。
-丹:你們好嗎,小夥子們？
-你喜歡威士忌嗎？
-嗯。
布萊恩: 哦,是嗎？
-那是給你的。
-謝謝。
布萊恩？
-艾琳,你知道艾瑪,你知道嗎？
“在那裡。
你過得更好
回家吧,姑娘。
他對你來說有點老了。
布萊恩:你在幹什麼？
你曾經在什麼世界里想過
這是合適的嗎？
你在說什麼？
為了他媽的緣故,
你認為誰
我到底是,媽媽？
嘿 嘿。不要把手放進去
在你母親身上。
（布萊恩·葛籣茨）
-騙子,什麼...騙子！
-你真他媽的丟臉。
（兩人都咕嚕咕嚕）
布萊恩: 從我身上下來！（咕嚕咕嚕）
下車！
（呼吸沉重）
（咕嚕咕嚕繼續）
（沖頭）
（氣喘吁吁）
（康呻吟）
（車門關閉）
（發動機啟動）
（發動機轉速）
如果你在這裡大喊大叫,
別他媽的打擾。
我要出去了。
布萊恩:想像一下
會是什麼樣子
一年後到這裡？
這是投資
繞著我們,就像。
你什麼都感覺不到嗎
關於發生了什麼,不是嗎？
關於莎拉...
你對她做了什麼？
別看我
像這樣,你會嗎？
這是否意味著
對你來說絕對沒什麼？
難道沒有心嗎
還是有感覺在你裡面？
上帝啊！
你有這個
我不可能的形象,愛琳。
讓我們繼續前進,
好吧？
我要你離開我們的生活。
（抽泣）
（氣喘吁吁）
（海鷗吱吱叫）
（艾琳氣喘吁吁）
（咕嚕咕嚕）
（雷鳴）
布萊恩: 媽媽！
媽媽！
（尖叫）媽媽！
（抽泣）
（敲門）
愛琳:莎拉,
愛,我可以介入嗎？
我很慚愧,姑娘。
坐在你的房子里。
我很抱歉
打擾你,我...
我不知道為什麼我必須這樣做。我。。。
我不是在解釋自己。
你不應該離開。
過去幾周的風...
這些房子是
真他媽的壞。
我想這就是
瑪麗聽到了。
所有房間都有馬克的聲音。
只是風吹過。
我過去聽的方式
晚上給我母親,
把爸爸抱到床上
當他生氣的時候。
聽到她四處走動
然後,當晚剩下的時間里,
對自己哭泣。
我只是躺在那裡
在我自己的房間里。
二十年前,
我仍然能聽到他們的回聲。
我想每個房子
這裡周圍有同樣的鬼魂。
媽媽為這個事實感到驕傲
她能夠
離開我這個房子。
在她之後,我會住在這裡,
等等...
直到潮汐帶走它。
我曾經醒來的所有時間
在你的房子里,愛琳...
布萊恩在我旁邊的床上。
同樣的風
讓我每天晚上都保持清醒。
是他的聲音嗎
這困擾著我...
和所有其他鬼魂一起？
過去的雷聲進入。
（歎息）因為
突然之間,我...
我不知道我在哪裡。
好像這所房子
它的所有歷史都不是我的。
（深深地歎息）
（發動機啟動）
(DOG BARKING)
FRANCIE: Long day ahead.
(BARKING CONTINUES
IN THE DISTANCE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Aileen?
Thanks, love.
SARAH: More like
donkeys broken in, Mary.
Fuck's sake, like,
we could have been anything.
Teachers, nurses, hairdressers.
(CHUCKLES) Hairdressers?
Don't be so ambitious, Sarah.
Did you not just hear her
calling us donkeys?
Actual asses, like.
-But what an arse, Sheila, girl.
-(LAUGHTER)
(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
MARY: My son! (SOBBING)
No!
Mark! (CRYING HYSTERICALLY)
(MARY CRYING SOFTLY)
(SARAH SINGING IN GAELIC)
If I do nothing else,
I'm teaching this little fecker
how to swim.
SARAH: Erin.
Jesus Christ, girl.
Yera...
for fuck's sake.
They literally live on the water
and none of them learn how.
You know
it's the tradition, Erin.
What, it's bad luck to know?
If they can't swim,
they won't jump in
and help anyone else.
Pack of selfish wankers,
too worried
about their own skins.
-(OSCAR COOING)
-What's wrong, Oscar, love?
Wakes up crying three,
four times a night.
-Disaster, like.
-Jesus Christ,
I remember nights with you.
Could never sleep.
Con telling me
I just had to let you cry.
How could I do that?
-Hearing every noise.
-(COOING)
You were the easier child,
to be fair.
(COOING)
(SINGING IN GAELIC)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
BRIAN: How's it going?
I haven't see you in a while.
How's things?
Good to see you. (LAUGHS)
(LAUGHTER)
Hi, Dan.
Brian O'Hara? What the hell
are you doing here?
Jesus Christ, the size of you.
The stronger you get...
Come here.
BRIAN: We're all wider
and wiser by the look Dan boy.
-After a while.
-Well boy, how's things?
Brian.
-Christ, Brian...
-(LAUGHS)
Mom, look at you, huh.
-Your hair.
You haven't changed a bit.
-(CRYING)
(OSCAR CRYING)
BRIAN: Who's this, huh?
It's my baby brother, is it?
What! No, no, no.
Jesus Christ. (LAUGHS)
Oh, come here to me.
Oh. (PANTING)
Well, Paddy, how's things?
ERIN: You son of a bitch.
-Brian!
-BRIAN: Erin!
What the fuck!
What are you doing here?
It's 'bout time
I came back, isn't it?
(SIGHS)
-BRIAN: Sarah.
-Brian.
ERIN: It takes Mark Fitz dying
for you to come back
to us, does it?
What?
That's who this is for?
Ah, fuck me, it is.
I'm so sorry.
Just give me one second.
Mary, um...
I'm so sorry, Mary.
-I'm so sorry.
-MARY: Thank you.
How long has Paddy
been like this?
A good few years now
at this stage.
-Must be weird being back.
-Hmm.
Probably the exact fuckin' same,
though, is it?
(BRIAN AND ERIN LAUGH)
BRIAN: Does she ever stop going?
ERIN: Oh, not a second
all the time you were gone.
(OSCAR CRYING)
ERIN: One minute, love.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
BRIAN: That dad, is it?
You should go out and meet him.
He'd like that.
Go on.
-You good?
-Oh yeah, yeah.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
ERIN: Strange seeing them
shake hands.
(AILEEN SIGHS) He's different,
isn't he? Grown into himself.
Do you reckon?
AILEEN: A mother knows.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
The look on your face.
-Don't be so shocked, mate.
-What?
-CON: Has she fed you?
-BRIAN: Uh, no. Not yet.
CON: Hard to believe
he's home, huh?
Good to be home now, all right.
So, you're in Australia.
Not been in touch
with us in how long?
And you get a notion,
all of a sudden, to come home.
Shit weather, fuck all work,
and not tell anyone?
Yeah. That's about
the size of it, yeah.
Come on, why are you back, like?
Uh...
Paddy's oysters.
Christ. Oh, you be starting
from nothing again.
Have you money saved?
Oysters take work.
They aren't cheap.
But we still have
the license for it.
I kept up the payments.
Every year
since Con gave up on it.
Just in case.
(HUMMING)
(CON GRUNTS)
-Tilt it forward.
-Okay.
-BRIAN: Is it that way?
-Yes.
-BRIAN: That all right?
-Yeah.
BRIAN: I see
you looked after it.
CON: My father
wasn't able for it anymore,
and you were gone
and stayed gone.
That was that. No other option.
Didn't want to work it
with anyone else.
Jesus Christ, it's unreal.
CON: Ground's
a bit soft in parts.
You'll have to replace
some of your trestles.
Find a supplier
for your oysters and bags.
Start with seeds
or half-growns, then.
Be a year at least
before they mature, turn profit.
You'll have to find
another income.
But you know that yourself.
That's nothing
you can't manage,
though, Brian. Is it?
Not a bother.
For fuck's sake. (CHUCKLES)
(CLANGING)
Oh, sorry, Aileen.
Forgot to clock out.
-Just give me a minute.
-No rush, love.
BRIAN: Fine looking oysters.
Thanks, Francie.
Be some craic if they caught us.
-AILEEN: Oh,
don't say that to me.
-(LAUGHS)
Hurry up will you. Come on.
I'm waiting on you, Mom.
(GRUNTS)
-See you for dinner, yeah?
-Go on, aye, go away.
Be safe.
-BRIAN: Hup!
-(LIVELY IRISH MUSIC PLAYING)
(AILEEN WHOOPING)
(CHEERING)
BRIAN: Thank you, guys.
Hi, boy, how're things?
DAN: There you are.
Here, take some of this. Go on.
FRANCIE: C'mon. Give us a song.
-Go on.
-Thanks, Mom.
-There you go, Dan.
-SARAH: Okay, all right.
I'll do one for you.
鈾?We go walking in the dark
鈾?We go walking out at night
(WOMAN SHUSHES)
鈾?And it's not as lovers go
鈾?Two by two, to and fro,
鈾?But it's one by one
鈾?One by one in the dark
鈾?We go walking out at night
What about Australia?
鈾?As we wander
through the grass
-What was your
favorite place down there?
-Hmm.
鈾?We can hear each other pass
You'd be surprised
how little I saw of it, Aileen.
If I'd known where you were,
I'd have gone and visited you.
鈾?We go walking out at night
That would have
been nice all right, but...
you didn't miss much.
鈾?Grass so dark and tall
(CHUCKLES)
Besides, it's the
best thing in the world
being back here...
with you.
鈾?And the moon is down
鈾?We go walking out at night
鈾?If I held your hand in mine
鈾?I could shine, I could shine
鈾?Like the morning sun
鈾?Like the sun 鈾?/i>
(ALL APPLAUDING)
-Where you off to?
-MARY: Could I get another, Dan?
-I'm going for a smoke.
-No, no, no.
You're not going anywhere.
-We've gotta go home.
-No. I don't want to go home.
-I don't care.
-I don't want to go home yet.
(MUTTERS)
Mary, huh?
-MARY: No.
-Come on.
FRANCIE: I'm telling you
the count is low.
SHEILA: Count them again.
FRANCIE: I counted them twice.
There aren't enough bags.
SHEILA: You telling me
how to do my job, Francie?
FRANCIE: Someone's
trying to cheat me.
Is it going to come out
of your fucking wages?
SHEILA: Listen, I'm only
giving you what you asked for.
FRANCIE: Oh, hold on.
You're saying
it has to do with me!
-It's my fault now, is it?
-Hey, hey, what's
the story here, lads?
This little bitch
is trying to cheat me.
Fuck off, Francie.
There isn't
near enough bags there.
Where's the rest
of my fuckin' half-growns?
I'm sure they're all there.
You filled them right,
didn't you?
Can't imagine
how I couldn't have.
I split them the exact same way
as I did last time, like.
Cause you're a moron,
that's why. Is Dennis here?
AILEEN: I haven't
seen him yet, no.
It's an easy mistake to make,
girl. Go on away quick.
(SEAGULLS SQUAWK)
It's crazy inside there,
isn't it?
Shame you and Francie
had to go home early on us
the other night.
I've been taking space,
and he's not been happy
about it.
Wiped my hands of him
after the last night.
But here I am crying my eyes out
as if he's the one
who broke my heart.
Can't help it, though.
Take your time with it.
I've been back
in my parents' house
a couple of nights.
Time puts it all
into perspective very quickly.
He was brutal with his words.
Still, though, he's just
like anyone else really.
We're all God's creatures
in the dark.
(AILEEN SIGHS)
(AILEEN SPEAKS GAELIC)
(GASPS)
BRIAN: That's four salmon.
Two hundred to you.
DRIVER: Good man.
-BRIAN: Thanks.
-Cheers.
BRIAN: How's work going, Con?
Ah, coining it, I suppose.
Where's this come from?
You think you're
a hard man, do you?
Fighting the system.
Poaching alone,
as if you didn't know better.
It's nothing you didn't do
back in the day, Con.
I never went out
on spring tides.
Sure Mark died
doing the same thing.
And that's either
what will happen to you
eventually, or you'll be caught.
All points to the same end,
like. Stupidity.
Jesus Christ, lighten up, mate.
The bags she stole for you
weren't enough, no?
You lasted all of about how long
making an honest go
of the oysters?
Longer than I reckoned anyway.
Fair play to you.
You keep telling me
what I can and can't do,
but I'm keeping
Paddy's farm going.
Your father's only trying to say
that you don't have to take
such a risk.
Thanks for that, Mom.
(WATER GUSHING)
(SEAGULLS SQUAWK
IN THE DISTANCE)
What's the story here, lad?
Checking if there isn't anything
I can make use of.
Christ, things are
that bad, are they?
You're like a rat.
Most of this is my old shite.
It's long past being any use.
Invest in a few new things
for yourself.
Give yourself
a chance anyway, boy.
Tell us, what...
what are you doing tomorrow?
(CLICKS TONGUE) Uh...
head out in the evening
after the tide, I'd say.
So, you're free
in the morning, I take it?
Could have a job for you.
I mean, use these away sure
and I could pay you
a bit extra on top.
It's tough, isn't it...
doin' it by yourself?
It's too much, really,
for one man.
It's the lesson
your father learned.
These would fit Brian,
would they?
Are you all right, Mary?
I keep thinking I hear Mark
when I'm here alone.
A sound at night...
and it might be him
moving around the place.
Strange comfort.
(SIGHS)
Thanks, love.
(PANTING)
FRANCIE: Brian,
come out the fuck.
Can you hurry up?
(GRUNTS)
Oh.
-Oh.
-(LAUGHS)
Got to keep an eye
on the tide, mate.
(GROANS)
BRIAN: Some morning out there,
Paddy Boy.
Everything supposedly shifts,
but...
it's exactly like it was
when you, me,
and Con were workin' it.
Drinking cold tea
out of a 7UP bottle
on a clear day,
there's nothing like it.
Are you there at all?
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Shit...
Fuck...
Dick, bollocks, arse.
(COOING SOFTLY)
You didn't say anything?
ERIN:
I didn't tell him nothing, no.
Nine months later, this fella.
He's a needy little fecker.
The usual family traits.
Boys being boys.
Stuck to their mother's tit.
Lookin' very smart.
Do you want
to come down with us?
ERIN: I should head home.
We've an early one
in the morning.
Heading up the country
for a few days.
Show the small man
there's more to the world.
BRIAN: Come on.
Let's go show you off.
Oh.
(CHUCKLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(LAUGHS)
I... I don't know.
-Christmas jumper.
-Christmas jumper,
that's the one.
Okay, um...
you could go
anywhere in the world.
No conditions.
Where would you go?
Do you know what...
I'd rather just... (SIGHS)
reel the years back in...
and sit you
and your father down
and make ye act like adults.
It's nice
imagining you getting along,
living under the one roof.
But I'm proud the way
you are now, though.
It's as if the work itself
was the beginning
and the end of it.
SARAH: Hey, Dan.
-DAN: Hey, Sarah.
-Can I get a whiskey, please?
You can, of course. Yeah.
Did you want another drink?
No. No, stay there.
I'll get it, all right.
Let me get you this.
Oh, you're grand.
Thanks, though.
You out for the night?
We'll see now after this one.
Mmm-hmm.
I can't believe
you're still here, to be honest.
I thought you would have
long abandoned this place.
I don't know
why you'd think that.
Everything I ever needed
was here.
Didn't have to go
looking for it.
Hmm.
Like what?
Nah. We used to have
a good craic together
when we were younger, didn't we?
-Us?
-Mmm-hmm.
It was so long ago.
I wouldn't get hung up on it
if I were you.
What are you drinking?
Go on sure, surprise me.
I, um... two of the same again.
-Uh, she's having
whiskey, is she?
-DAN: Mmm-hmm.
-(CLANKING)
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
BRIAN: There you go.
There's...
What time is low tide due?
Go on, will you?
All right. Night, pet.
Good night.
SARAH: I might borrow
that top off you
one of the nights, Aileen.
AILEEN: I'll see you
tomorrow, girl.
(CROW SQUAWKS)
AILEEN: Sorry, lads.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-Good morning.
-ALL: Good morning.
WOMAN 1:
Were you out last night?
WOMAN 2: No, no.
I was not. Were you out?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Good night so, was it?
WOMAN: Mary, look.
-Look at that.
-Stop the belt. Aileen.
-Fungus.
-Shit.
WOMAN: We've got fungus, too.
DENNIS: Let me see that!
-Check the rest of the stock.
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
DENNIS: Throw these ones out.
Fuck's sake!
What a disaster.
(CONTINUES BREATHING HEAVILY)
WOMAN: Jesus!
-Sarah?
-Don't touch me.
PATROLMAN WEST:
You are hereby warned
to cease cultivation
of all oyster holdings
until further notice,
punishable by loss of license
if caught in breach
of the moratorium.
Any oysters you harvested today
must be destroyed.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
BRIAN: Do you have
any work for me?
FRANCIE: No, I'm not gonna
need you again
for a while, no.
Keep your head down
like the rest of 'em,
you'll be grand.
I'll take what you owe me, so.
(FRANCIE LAUGHS)
FRANCIE: All right, lads,
let's throw them all out. Yeah.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SHOWER RUNNING)
-WOMAN 1: What are we
supposed to do now, like?
-WOMAN 2: Oh.
WOMAN 3: Same thing happened,
about seven or eight years ago,
didn't it?
Nearly destroyed
the oyster farmers.
WOMAN 2: The idea of them
at home doing nothing.
No good for anyone.
MARY: It seems to be gotten
worse and worse for her,
doesn't it?
Poor cratur.
She didn't mean to bite at you.
If Francie's done something,
she needs to speak up about it.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-ERIN: Hey, love.
-Hiya.
Are you busy?
Not a great time, no.
I'm just doing
a few jobs on the house.
Mom says they haven't seen you
in the factory in a few days.
The smell's finally
getting to you, is it?
No.
What's after happening, girl?
I'm here, you know.
If you need anything. Yeah?
Yeah.
I'll let you get back to it.
Thanks.
(CAR DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(ENGINE STARTS, REVS)
(SIGHS)
(BRIAN GRUNTS)
(PHONE RINGING)
CON: Hello?
Aileen.
Aileen. How are things?
Hey, you might follow me
through here now.
We're just in here now, look.
How's Con gettin' on?
Where's Brian, Mike?
Sorry to drag you
all the way into town.
You must be delighted
to have Brian
back in the house with you.
Sure, you know yourself.
Do you reckon?
God knows if my girls
moved back into the house,
we'd be tearing strips
off each other.
Australia he was, was it?
Australia, yeah.
Isn't that always the way?
Breaking his mother's heart.
Exactly.
Look, there's been a claim made
about an assault in the village
a couple of weeks back
by a young woman
who was in Dan Nell's pub
on the night
of the 18th of April.
Brian says he was at home
with you that night.
Is that right?
He was, yeah.
-He didn't go out
or anything at any stage...
-No. No.
And you'd say that again
in court?
I would. Yeah.
All right. Look, I know,
well, Brian's
a hard-workin' fella.
Is that it?
I'll give him a shout
for you there now. One minute.
It's a bit much, Mike, isn't it,
to drag me out
in the middle of the night
just to ask a simple question?
We've to be seen to be
doing our job, Aileen.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Are you all right?
Huh. Need to go for a few pints.
My van is on the way back.
We might pick it up.
Was there anyone else out,
do you remember?
I couldn't tell you.
What happened after I left you?
We had a few drinks.
Nothing we didn't do
back in the day.
What does that mean?
Jesus Christ...
Am I better off going back
to fucking Australia?
Is that it? Getting dragged
into this shit.
You're not going
anywhere, all right?
Do you hear me?
(WATER FLOWING)
(CROW CAWING)
Thanks, Mom.
MARY: The moratorium
won't last, is the point.
In a couple of weeks,
the water will cool,
all will magically reset.
Oyster farmers coining it again,
like nothing ever happened.
That's what time does.
Lesson wasted on the young.
WOMAN: Aileen? Aileen.
Are there any extra hours
I can pick up next week?
You might cover Sarah's shifts.
You haven't heard from her?
I have. Yeah.
We've had Guards into us.
Yera, no...
they were just looking
to talk to customers
who were in a few weeks back.
It was a quiet night...
That's what I told them.
It'd be more in their line now
to be looking into
foreign trawlers raping
our oceans, huh?
Their hands are tied,
that's what
they'll tell you anyway.
Why wasn't Jesus
born in Australia?
Oye.
-Ah, 'cause he was...
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
EMMA: Night, lads.
-DAN: All right.
-Yeah.
Are you in with us
tomorrow again, girl?
I am, yeah. Thanks.
-Night to you.
-DAN: Night.
BRIAN: Night.
Because there was no wise men...
No virgins either.
(BRIAN CHUCKLES)
-All right.
-Hmm.
DAN: Good man.
-Come on...
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-DAN: Night.
-OLD MAN: Night to you. Night.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Is Brian in?
(OSCAR COOING)
A charge is gonna be
brought against him.
He needs to present himself
in front of the district court
today week,
and an initial remand
will be made
in front of a judge.
For fuck sake, Mike.
Look, just make sure
he's there, will you?
ERIN: You told them
you weren't out that night.
But we both know
that's a lie, though.
What do you know about it, Erin?
There's Francie mistreating her
for how many years,
and nobody
thinks anything of it.
And suddenly everyone reckons
that Brian's the problem.
Who never put a hand
on a woman in his life.
You said yourself something
was after happening to Sarah.
Maybe it was Francie, yeah.
But you don't want
to hear her side?
Are you all right?
DENNIS: Sarah's
not in again today?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
What time will you be back?
I don't know.
What happens
if he's returned for trial?
PADDY:
鈾?At waking time and sleeping
鈾?It's there I'd long to be
鈾?To walk again
鈾?Those kindly streets
鈾?The place where I was born
Come on.
How does it finish?
Hmm?
鈾?With the boys
from Barr na Sraide
鈾?Who hunted
BRIAN AND PADDY:
鈾?For the wren... 鈾?/i>
(CHUCKLES)
There's nothing
wrong with you, Paddy, mate.
Hmm.
You're only playing a trick
on the rest of us.
What other songs do you have?
A verse of McAlpines? Hmm?
A blast of The Wild Rover maybe?
Good man.
Hm.
MIKE: The complainant
waited a week
before making her report
and claims she was
followed down to the local pier
on the night of the assault
and that the defendant
subsequently raped her
down there.
The defendant's mother
has provided him
with an alibi, Judge.
And she reaffirms the statement
that she and the defendant
were in the house
during the hours
of the night in question,
that the defendant remained
in the house with her
during the hours
of the claimed assault?
I do, Your Honor. Yes.
JUDGE: Hmm.
This is a serious accusation.
It's also the first time
the defendant
has been before the court.
Now it's my opinion
that there's not enough...
in the Book of Evidence
for the State to prosecute.
Charges will be remanded
back to the DPP
for further instructions.
I also believe that this charge
should not have been
brought before the court.
Uh, the defendant
is free to leave.
What's next?
MIKE: File 15, Judge.
Drunk and disorderly.
(SIGHS)
(WATER GUSHING)
(EXHALES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
DENNIS: Aileen.
Come here a minute, will you?
What's her attendance lately?
Fourteen of 16 shifts missed.
SARAH: I can make
the days up. Please.
DENNIS: Has anyone else
missed a shift in the same time?
You could have let us know
at least, you know,
called in sick.
But I have to let you go, girl.
You're right, Dennis.
I should've let you know
what's been happening with me.
That was the mistake, yeah?
It's all very convenient
for you, though, isn't it?
Between Francie's oyster bags
and everything else,
everyone's got their
fucking eyes closed.
DENNIS: Wait, hang on a second.
Sarah?
What about
the oyster bags, Sarah?
Come on lads, focus,
back on the work.
What does she mean
about Francie's oysters, Aileen?
Go home.
-What?
-Go home for the day.
(AILEEN GIGGLING)
(COOING)
Oscar, love.
You can't just take him
out of daycare
without telling me.
He's not your son.
I don't want you
looking after him anymore.
Fuck's sake, Erin.
She's still his grandmother.
If you'd actually sit with her,
you wouldn't be able to deny
what happened so easily, Aileen.
-CON: Go easy on her.
-ERIN: No.
For fuck's sake,
she needs to hear it.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
CON: I'll talk to her.
You have to be careful with him.
And all the time
that Sarah was in here,
when it was Erin's room.
I used to joke with her mother
about the two of you,
that we'd be in-laws.
DENNIS: Was she lying
about the oyster bags, Aileen?
I'm gonna have to put you
on the line until I figure out
what the story is.
Moratorium's been lifted.
Be a mad few weeks.
Might have to hire
a few more hands.
(CONTINUES TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
DAN: So the story went round,
and for months,
people thought the wife died
'cause she'd fallen down
the well tryin' to save
the turkey.
It was some clever prick,
the guard.
WOMAN 1: It'd be great
to have you all over
next Sunday after mass.
WOMAN 2:
Give you a rest for once.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Be a break for you.
DAN: As if he'd been
waiting for that question
the entire time.
-(LAUGHTER)
-WOMAN 1: I'll do
my apple crumble.
"Because she was
an annoying bitch, that's why."
(LAUGHTER)
SHEILA: Two gins
and a tonic, please?
DAN: Not tonight, no.
SHEILA: What?
DAN: We retain the right
to refuse service here, love.
Do yourself a favor
and go quietly.
Hmm?
You can all go to fuckin' hell.
(LAUGHTER)
DAN: You stay
where you are now, lad.
-Hold on to him there, boys.
-(LOUD LAUGHTER)
Don't you go
following her now, eh?
(LOUD LAUGHTER)
(GRUNTS)
BRIAN: I hate
these traditional things.
Showing face
just for the sake of it.
I might not bother going.
Do what you want.
(SEAGULL SQUAWKS)
鈾?I who made the stars of night
鈾?I will make
their darkness bright
鈾?Who will bear
my light to them?
鈾?Whom shall I send?
鈾?Here I am, Lord
鈾?Is it I, Lord?
鈾?I have heard
鈾?You calling in the night
鈾?I will go, Lord
鈾?If you lead me
鈾?I will hold
鈾?Your people in my heart
鈾?Here I am, Lord
鈾?Is it I, Lord?
鈾?I have heard
(RAIN PATTERING)
鈾?You calling in the night
鈾?I will go, Lord
鈾?If you lead me
鈾?I will hold... 鈾?/i>
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIGHS)
(CLANGING)
It's a late tide today.
CON: Aileen.
Aileen, would you come in here?
I'll, uh...
MARY: ...Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb Jesus.
ALL: Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
MARY: Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb Jesus.
ALL: Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
MARY: Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb Jesus.
ALL: Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
MARY: Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb Jesus.
ALL: Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
MARY: Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb Jesus.
ALL: Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
MARY: Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee...
(CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
-MAN: Sorry for your loss.
-Thank you.
-WOMAN: Sorry for your loss.
-ERIN: Thank you.
Thank you.
WOMAN 1: I'm so sorry
for your loss.
Thank you.
WOMAN 2: I'm so sorry
for your loss.
(AILEEN BREATHING HEAVILY)
-MAN: I'm sorry for your loss.
-Thanks.
-MAN: Sorry for your loss.
-Thank you.
I'm sorry for your loss, Con.
CON: Thanks, Sarah.
-NIGEL: Sarah!
-Don't fuckin' touch her.
-NIGEL: Condolences
for your loss, Brian.
-Thanks.
Seems like the whole world
has turned upside down.
It's just as fucked
as it's ever been, Mom.
It might look different
if you're the one turning.
But...
nothing's changed.
Trust me.
You were right stepping in
like that, though.
We're going to head home.
Get some rest.
You should, too.
(BUGGY WHEELS ROLLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Huh?
BRIAN: What do you want?
Um, whiskey, I guess.
-You want whiskey?
-Yeah.
BRIAN: Here,
two whiskeys, please.
DAN: Two whiskeys, huh?
-EMMA: Yeah.
-BRIAN: You look great.
-EMMA: Thanks.
-DAN: How're ye, lads?
-Do you like whiskey, you do?
-Hmm.
BRIAN: Oh, yeah?
-That one's for you.
-Thanks.
Brian?
-Aileen, you know Emma, you do?
-Hi.
You're better off
going home, girl.
He's a bit old for you.
BRIAN: What are you doing?
In what world did you ever think
that this would be appropriate?
What're you talking about?
For fuck's sake,
who do you think
I am at all, Mom?
Hey, hey. Don't put your hands
on your mother.
(BRIAN GRUNTS)
-Con, what the... Con!
-You're a fucking disgrace.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
BRIAN: Get off me! (GRUNTS)
Get off!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(PUNCHES)
(PANTING)
(CON GROANS)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVS)
If you're here to shout,
don't fuckin' bother.
I'm going out.
BRIAN: Imagine
what it'll be like
out here in a year?
This is the investment
round us, like.
Do you not feel anything
about what's happened, no?
About Sarah...
about what you did to her?
Don't look at me
like that, will you?
Does it mean
absolutely nothing to you?
Is there no heart
or feeling in you?
Jesus Christ!
You have this
impossible image of me, Aileen.
Let's just move forward,
all right?
I want you out of our lives.
(SOBBING)
(PANTING)
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
(AILEEN PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
BRIAN: Mom!
Mom!
(SCREAMS) Mom!
(SOBBING)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
AILEEN: Sarah,
love, can I step in?
I'm ashamed, girl.
Sitting in your house.
I'm sorry to be
bothering you, I...
I don't know why I had to. I...
I'm not explaining myself.
You shouldn't be leaving.
The wind the past few weeks...
These houses are
so fuckin' bad for it.
I suppose that's what
Mary was hearing.
Sound of Mark in all the rooms.
Just the wind getting through.
The way I used to listen
to my mother at nights,
carrying Dad down to bed
when he'd be pissed.
Hearing her moving around
the rest of the night then,
crying away to herself.
Me just lying there
in my own room.
Twenty years ago,
and I can still hear their echo.
I suppose every house
around here has the same ghosts.
Mom was so proud of the fact
that she was able
to leave me this house.
I'd live here after she did,
and so on...
until the tide takes it.
All the times I used to wake up
in your house, Aileen...
Brian in the bed beside me.
That same wind
keeping me awake every night.
Is it the sound of him
that's haunting me...
with all these other ghosts?
The thunder of pasts getting in.
(SIGHS) Because
all of a sudden, I...
I don't know where I am.
As if this house
and all its history wasn't mine.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(ENGINE STARTS)